# **ALESHA REED**

# Software Engineer

## CONTACT

Phone: 615-481-1216
Email: aleshak83@gmail.com
LinkedIn:@alesha-reed
https://www.aleshareed.com
https://github.com/aleshakay

### **ABOUT ME**

Passionate Software Engineer with years of experience troubleshooting and working with dynamic teams to support and maintain front end web applications for a large enterprise. Working in an environment with talented individuals I felt driven to learn more about the applications that I support. Driven by that desire to understand I enrolled and completed a full stack web development bootcamp.

My goal is to provide full stack support by designing and developing web applications while delivering a stellar product in the areas of performance and usability.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- React
- HTML
- CSS
- LITIUX
- Technical Documentation
- SOL

- Microsoft IIS
- AWS
- .NET Core
- C#
- Kubernetes
- GitHub
- JSON

## **EDUCATION**

# NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

#### MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Business Administration, Major in Computer Information Systems

### **TECHNICAL EDUCATION**

# NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL (CURRENT) Full Stack Web Developer

Enrolled in a part-time 12-month bootcamp at Nashville Software School that facilitates an environment that cultivates a problem-solving mindset and technical tools to become a full stack web developer.

Technical Skills: Javascript, React, SASS, CSS, HTML, GitHub, JSON, .NET, C#, SQL, ERD, Agile

### **PROJECTS**

### Magical Memories

Magical memories is a single page CRUD photography appointment scheduling application created with React.

Magical memories enables clients with the ability to schedule, update, and cancel photography appointments. It uses Firebase, a JSON database to store data about clients, photographs, and photographers that are each entities required by the application. While in the application react router dom is utilized to route users between the different available views.

Magical Memories URL: https://magicalmemories-afe4d.firebaseapp.com/ Github: https://github.com/aleshakay/Magical-Memories/

### ClinkedIn

ClinkedIn a C# application that modeled a social network for prisoners. In the application I was able to use both the repository and controller to select the services and add those services to the selected prisoner. In ClinkedIn, my group used scrum framework with agile methodology to deliver features specified by the project documentation. We assessed our

achievements and losses consistently throughout the group mini project.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Asurion | 2013 - present

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 2015 - PRESENT**

- Create monitoring solutions in Elastic and AWS for use by internal global operations team to maintain high service level for enterprise applications.
- Migrate web application to AWS Elastic Kubernetes Service to standardize and increase supportability by creating a base model for all cluster builds.
- Create and maintain documentation to assist in providing technical teams steps to resolve errors and exceptions for nine major product launches.
- Address technical issues through creation of automated chatbot processes to alert and remediate externally facing webpage outages.

### **OPERATIONS ENGINEER | 2013 - 2015**

- Provided root cause analysis for critical middle tier, .NET, and user interface incidents which sustained or met a service level availability of 99%.
- Deployed operational level changes into non-production and production environments.
- Reduced release time during database migrations through creation of powershell scripts to update connection strings across stacks of .NET servers.
- Formalized the processes for troubleshooting through the creation of runbooks and providing knowledge transfers for IT support teams.